Silva, Murillo

S-4 Street - Bela Vista - Goiania murillov.dev@gmail.com | +55 62 983-196-600 www.linkedin.com/in/murillo-vieira

SUMMARY

Having more than 5 years of experience in the field as a Frontend and Fullstack developer, I've worked on important projects in every phase of the software development lifecycle, from business requirements collection to project delivery. Throught the code, I always try to add value to the company being aware of the company's perspectives and goals.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Led a team of 4 Frontend developers and increased the amount of tasks delivered by the team by 25% per Sprint
- 2. Incremented the developers productivity by 10% by creating automated tools and by writing detailed documentation
- 3. Identified performance issues an cut down the screen render time by four times, also reducing overfetch
- 4. Given talks to a large community. Also helped 5 other people from coding basics to mid-level
- 5. Had participate of programming marathons at college and have won one local contest among 10 another teams

CAREER

Frontend Developer at Nectar CRM

Biggest CRM company in Brazilian's midwest Nov 2018 – Present • 2 yrs , 1 mos

Nectar is a regional CRM company which provides solutions for companies to manage relationships with their customers, selling procedures, Business Intelligence and a lot more. Integrated with Google, RD Station and a huge set of tools and enterprises, it helps companies boosts their sales process and strategy.

Responsibilities:

- Refactor of the Webapp with the new UX/UI set
- Development of new functionalities to the main software
- Create personalized documentation to help new hired developers to understand the applications
- Helped developing the new Mobile Application using React Native
- Development of Nectar CRM's main web app and bug solving issues
- Improvements on company's Backoffice app

Tech Stack:

AngularJS, Karma, ReactJS, React Native, Redux, Vue 2, HTML5, ES7, CSS3, Sass, Rest, Gulp, JSP, Git, Java 8.

Mobile Application Developer and Web Developer at Clubien

Wellness Delivery startup in Ireland
Jul 2020 – Present • 5 mos

Clubien is a Dublin-based startup who helps people Find the best beauty and grooming professionals and book treatments at home.

Main Mobile Developer:

- Lead of Clubien's Mobile APP development
- UI and UX primary responsible
- Enforce a reliable app performance and integrity

Web Developer:

- Improvements at Clubien's website and creation of the landing pages for customers and professionals
- Co-development of Admin's interface, Rest integration with company API

Tech Stack:

React Native, NextJS, React, Redux, Jest, Rest, Git.

Frontend Developer at Actuar

Leading provider of academic software in Brazil Jul 2017 – Nov 2018 • 1 yr 5 mos

Actuar is a company which focus on proving technology to gyms and web payment. As of August 2018, the company had approximately 2.000 throughout Brazil, more than 15.000 users from physic evaluation free webapp and thousands from TREI.NO app in Brazil and abroad. In 18 months I was able to:

- Lead a team of developers applying SCRUM and working on the development of an ERP focused on gyms management and crossfit boxes
- Estimate the effort for new demands and performed verification of the artifacts of software engineering such as requirements, design, implementation and testing
- Develop the math logic for payment methods, discounts and bonus
- Create webcomponent for scheduling software implantation and support inspection visits
- Give maintenance on a training app. Made responsive blogs and webpages for the company, also performing SEO

Tech Stack:

Angular 2+, Ionic 2, Typescript, Jest, Angular JS, Wordpress, Scrum, HTML5, ES6, CSS3, Sass, SVG, Git.

Fullstack Developer at Nussa Sistemas (Contractor)

Mar 2015 - Jun 2017 • 2 yrs, 4 mos

Description:

- Freelancer web developer, mobile apps, PWAs and websites
- Experience in data consumption and optimization

- Fullstack developer, responsible for handling entire Webapps from Backend to Frontend
- Webapps Deployment and its CI/CD

Some projects I worked for Nussa Sistemas were: mobile app for package delivery, PWA for medical congresses, daily liturgy webapp for Archdioceses and a Social Network including real time chat.

Tech Stack:

Angular 2+, Ionic 2+, React JS, React Native, Node JS + Express, Mongo DB, Firebase, CI/CD, Heroku, PHP and Wordpress.

Internship Software Developer at Meta

Feb 2017 – Jul 2017 • 6 mos

MetaTecnologia is a company with large experience in computerizing mobile phone shops. There I worked on the improvement of a product to control financial of mobile phone stores, and payment system integration to federal government. I was a Fullstack developer, I studied and handled a Fullstack setup.

Tech Stack:

JAVA, MongoDB, JSP, HTML and CSS with Bootstrap.

EDUCATION

University Degree

2014 - 2018 Universidade Federal de Goias

Bachelor of Computer Information Systems

Having also studied Computer Science since 2009, which included Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Compilers, Operating Systems, Algorithms and its Complexity.

Certificates

React Native with NodeJS and Firebase (28h); MERN Stack, Frontend to Backend (12h); Agile management with SCRUM (10h); Complete Javascript 2018 - Fundamentals to Master (35h); Web Design for Web Developers: UI/UX for Websites and Mobile (8h);

INTERESTS

- Help people to solve problems with code and great usability
- Grow as a developer and bring life to great ideas
- Know as many countries and cultures as possible

You can check out more at my personal website:

https://murilloves.github.io/dev/